<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>iamnotaninvestor</title>
  <id>http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com</id>
  <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com" />
  <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2014-06-10T23:32:20-04:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, iamnotaninvestor</rights>
  <author>
    <name>iamnotaninvestor</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/2014/06/introduction.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a stock market novice and am starting this blog to document my progress. I hope that writing this blog will force me to be more analytical and also force me to learn from my failures and successes. I&#39;d like to share those failures and successes with other novices in the hope that it may help. I&#39;m new to both fundamental and technical analysis and charting in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s with the Blog&#39;s Title?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not an investor. The title is a play on the fact that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) At this point in time I&#39;m just starting out and I really don&#39;t know what I&#39;m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) I&#39;m speculating, not investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c) I plan to daytrade and not purchase stocks for the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;About Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work as a software developer and have no (ZERO!) formal training or other experience investing in the stock market, nor do I have any market-insider friends. I am of reasonable intelligence, want to learn and have decided that the best way to do so is by jumping in. I&#39;ve have $10,000 that I&#39;m willing to invest and can tolerate losing. &#39;Tolerate&#39; being the operative... In the short-to-medium term I&#39;d like to double that figure via my returns. In the long term I would like to day-trade full time from home. Hopefully on a lake somewhere. We&#39;ll have to wait and see if either is feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why the Anonymity?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not a huge deal, but all being equal I&#39;d prefer to keep my finances private. Perhaps when I&#39;m actually making some money on the market I won&#39;t care as much. We&#39;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why Blog?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To keep myself honest. If I think deeply enough about my mistakes I won&#39;t repeat them. There are lessons to be learned both from losses and from gains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully, to earn some additional investment capital. I&#39;ll use affiliate links in the hope of generating some revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To document the process for anyone just starting out. I am a few weeks in and I&#39;ve already learned a massive amount. If I can impart any knowledge this will all be worthwhile!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;What Else do you Need to Know?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I repeat, I do not know what I&#39;m doing. Don&#39;t follow my trades blindly and certainly don&#39;t take me for a financial adviser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From time to time I will recommend products/platforms/books/materials. I will only recommend products that I like. I will fully disclose any products I&#39;ve been paid to use or rovided with free access to in exchange for a review. I will be objective in my reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is somewhat of a fluffy introductory post. Next, I&#39;ll review some of my prior trades (over the last 3-4 weeks).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/2014/06/introduction.html</id>
      <updated>2014-06-10T17:03:00Z</updated>
      <author>
        <name>iamnotaninvestor</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
