<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>iamnotaninvestor</title>
  <id>http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com</id>
  <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com" />
  <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2015-11-12T12:40:32-05:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, iamnotaninvestor</rights>
  <author>
    <name>iamnotaninvestor</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>The Great Unravelling</title>
      <link href="http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/2015/11/the-great-unravelling.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The month was June, 2014. Life was good. Every day the sun shone just a little longer and a little higher in the sky. And every day, for a while at least, my trades (almost all blue chip tech stocks. some IPOs, some not.) provided exciting returns for my somewhat meager outlay. Life was indeed good. But, beginner&#39;s luck is fickle. And, as I found out very quickly, luck was all I had in my arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;BRZG&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, Brazilian Gold (BRZG). It started with a tweet. A tweet from a guru intent on causing a ticker to move. After a couple of minutes I was up $1000. Not a massive sum, no. BUT quite a nice return for clicking a couple of buttons...I&#39;ve worked at least 40 hours a week, every single week, for as long as I can remember. Some people &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to work. For me, it&#39;s a means to an end. I make a nice salary but up to this point in my life I&#39;d never before made so much money so quickly. Visions of an easy and prosperous future clouded my judgement. I was up $1000 and should hae exited the trade, or at the very least sized down. But I didn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guru (supposedly) waited for a secondary push. So, I waited. The bid thinned up. And I waited. Profits were all but wiped out. And I waited. I broke all of my rules. Then I broke them again. I waited some more. A week later, down $2200, I swallowed my pride and got out of the trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if the guru was being honest, or if he used his following to move the ticker and take his profits at the expense of his audience. Maybe it was a pump and dump, maybe intentions were more pure - I really don&#39;t care. I had numerous opportunities to take a profit, numerous opportunities to size down and reduce my risk, numerous opporunities to minimize my loss. But I didn&#39;t take those opportunities. The market is never wrong. Other traders are my competitors. The loss was entirely my fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A chart, and a humorous aside&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the chart for BRZG around the time of my trade. I believe my entry was on 08/08/2014, but can&#39;t remember with certainty. I have no idea when my exit was (probably a week later) but watch the chart grind down thereafter. I&#39;d like to think that if I had been doing my own analysis, rather than blindly following a guru, I would have looked at the daily chart and realized that this ticker was going anywhere but up. The observant are probably asking why I&#39;m talking about BRZG, but showing a CNXS chart. BRZG, Brazilian Gold, is now CNXS...Conexus Cattle Corp. I&#39;m all for companies pivoting but you have to question the future of a company that moves from gold prospecting to cattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin:40px&quot;&gt;
&lt;!-- TradingView Chart BEGIN --&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tradingview/tv.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
var tradingview_embed_options = {};
tradingview_embed_options.width = document.getElementsByClassName(&quot;single-content&quot;)[0].clientWidth - 160;
tradingview_embed_options.height = 480;
tradingview_embed_options.chart = &#39;7k3zRf2J&#39;;
new TradingView.chart(tradingview_embed_options);
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- TradingView Chart END --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;!-- TradingView Chart END --&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Losses Add Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent another couple of weeks trading after my BRZG loss. I had numerous small profits and one large loss. The ticker was ZLCS (now EPRS?). For the second time in a couple of weeks I lost more than $1000 on a single trade. My win/loss ratio was pretty good but my risk management was non-existent. I fell into the common habit of cutting my winners but letting my losers ride, so each loss killed at lease three wins. It became quickly evident that if I stayed in the game, I would blow up my account. I stopped trading with the goal of learning my trade prior to investing more money. A smart move, in hindsight, and better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Noise, The Noise!!!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be incorrect to attribute my losses to a single cause. Many issues and many broken rules led to my bad trading, and the premature pause in my trading career. I&#39;ll cover the big ones in upcoming posts but, if there is only one piece of advice I can offer new traders it&#39;s to &lt;strong&gt;keep things simple&lt;/strong&gt;. I read many books, consumed thousands of tweets, dug into trading indicator after indicator, studied as many obscure chart patterns as I could get my hands on, downloaded every trading app available and frequented every notable trading site on the interwebs. I thought that the more information I could get my hands on, the better prepared i&#39;d be. But I was wrong. In the trading world, especially for novices, information overload leads to inertia. With so much noise, it is difficult to know in which direction to move. So you don&#39;t move. Or you move too slowly. Or, even worse, you blindly follow the herd. Reduce the noise as much as you possibly can. Forget about social media. Improve your focus. Concentrate on the basics - there&#39;ll be plenty of time for nuance later. If you start with a simple approach but lose money, you&#39;ll be in a better position to understand why. You&#39;ll learn and grow from the loss and, hopefully, be a better trader for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are. After a year out of the market my sabbatical is drawing to a close. After much soulsearching, researching and studying I&#39;m ready to dip my toes in the water again. So, I&#39;m giving this blog a reboot. I&#39;ve cleaned up past posts and in the next few months I&#39;m going to document the lessons I learned over the past 12 months and record my future trading successes and failures. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://www.iamnotaninvestor.com/2015/11/the-great-unravelling.html</id>
      <updated>2015-11-12T14:33:24-05:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>iamnotaninvestor</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
